# **AKI GAO**

xiaoyu.akihiro.gao@gmail.com | iknowhtml.github.io | github.com/iknowhtml

#### Profile

I am a JavaScript developer with a passion for technology and innovation, in particular the Web and Blockchain. I offer three years of experience in full stack web application development from conception through delivery of elegant and maintainable solutions using functional programming paradigms and test driven development in an Agile environment. My expertise ranges from designing and implementing responsive and user-friendly web-based UX/UIs to architecting and developing modular, scalable and fault-tolerant back end infrastructures. Specifically, I specialize in web application development using the React and Node, js ecosystems. I also have experience with Blockchain/DLT technologies and am actively involved its development and industry. My personal mission is to use technology and entreprenership to create a more compassionate and humancentric future by empowering people to connect more meaningfully and reducing social and economic inequality.

### Skills

#### Languages:

JavaScript, TypeScript, Shell (Bash)

#### UX/UI and Front End Technologies and Tools:

 Sketch, HTML, CSS, React, Redux, Redux-Saga/Thunk, React/Reach Router, CSS Modules, PostCSS

### Blockchain Technologies:

• Ethereum, Solidity, Web3.js, Ethers.js, Truffle, Metamask, Remix

#### Development and Testing Tools:

Agile (Scrum/Kanban), Git, NPM, Yarn, Webpack, Babel, Mocha,
Chai, Sinon, ESlint, Prettier

#### Back End and Database Technologies:

• Node.js, Express, GraphQL, Apollo, Mongoose, MongoDB

## Infrastructure and DevOps Technologies:

• Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, CircleCI, Travis, Terraform, Packer, AWS

## Work Experience

## Blockchain Web Application Development Consultant - Freelance/Contracting

February 2018 - Present

- Provides services to clients to architect and develop front end and back end applications for Blockchain-based platforms, as well as deployment to cloud.
- Also provides consultations to determine viability of Blockchain use cases and conceptualization of decentralized business models based on tokenization and distributed ledgers.
- Specializes in rapid prototyping of performant and user-friendly front end applications to interface with Blockchain back ends, as well as scalable hybrid back end solutions leveraging AWS that utilize both traditional database systems and Blockchain.

#### Alluminate - Javascript & Blockchain Developer

October 2017 - February 2018

- Provide high-level technology expertise and development capabilities for in-house and consulting work ranging from UX/UI to smart contract development.
- Designed, developed and maintained the company's homepage as well as the landing page for several products.
- Core development member of the CryptoPets platform, an Ethereum-based game platform for collecting and battling digital pets developed in partnership with Arcade Distillery.
- Aided in smart contract design, as well as audited smart contracts for correctness.
- Developed in-house development and testing environment using Web3, Docker and Geth.

## Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist

May 2017 - November 2017

- U.S. Treasury Proof of Concept Blockchain Application July 2017 August 2017
  - Developed a proof of concept Blockchain application using Ethereum for the U.S. Treasury to replace existing payment infrastructure between Government organizations.
  - Led development efforts across the stack, working with React and Redux the front end, Node and Express on the back end, as well as deploying the cloud infrastructure on Azure for the project in a small team of developers in an Agile environment using Kanban.
  - Acted as defacto Product Owner and Scrum Master to translate requirements from the stakeholder, and to convert requirements into tasks to be distributed among team members.
  - Participation, expertise and leadership in project led to conversion of project from a Proof of Concept work into a full-fledged proposal for a contract bid.
- FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment September 2017 November 2017
  - Architected and bootstrapped the front end for the FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment Project.
  - Led front end development efforts, including designing the UX/UI in Sketch, implementing application interface and logic with React and Redux, and providing high level guidance to other developers.

#### Education

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

• Computer Engineering & Electrical Engineering